MARIO V.

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mario-v-7ba41925

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Hardworking full stack developer, recent University of Denver coding boot camp graduate, and United States Air Force veteran with a Security+ certification and an active security clearance. Extensive SharePoint administration and front-end development experience in the defense and financial services industry. Experienced in development languages such as JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, React.js, MongoDB, and Git. Strong communication and collaboration skills with an established team of developers and project managers. Desire to be the catalyst that inspires my teammates and organization to prosper.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

DSoft Technology Company - February 2016 to Present (Senior Consultant)

- Provide administrative, development, training and analyst support for all in house SharePoint projects
- Administered Air Force Space Command's Space/Cyberspace Analysis Resource Portal
- Cybersecurity Liaison for Headquarters Air Force Space Command
- Develop custom SharePoint applications to help automate accounting processes
- Coordinated and performed Office 365 to Office 365 data and user migrations
- Designed SharePoint business intelligence tools to help analyze accounting data
- Created custom web forms and workflows for our clients
- Administrator of Office 365, SharePoint 2010 and SharePoint 2013 systems
- Key leader for in house process improvement initiatives
- Distributor of Office 365 licenses and subscriptions
- Cultivate new client relationships

Technology used: SharePoint 2013, SharePoint Online, O365, and Windows Server 2016

University of Denver (Student) - March 2019 to August 2019

- Created responsive frontend websites with the use of custom HTML5, CSS, and the use of Bootstrap
- Developed interactive projects with APIs, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Designed live web application using basic frontend code and incorporated a Firebase database
- Created Node.is based weather, concert, and movie search applications
- Engineered MySQL databases to store and retrieve web application data
- Use Git for project version control and for collaborating with team members
- Built React applications with a MongoDB backend

Technology used: Auth0, JavaScript, jQuery, Express, MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL, Mongoose, Node.JS, React.JS, Heroku, Handlebars, Sequalize, Git, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, Moment.JS, and Leaflet.JS

US Air Force Active Duty and US Air Force Reserve – Honorable Discharge 2017 (Electrical Systems Craftsman)

- Performed crisis management duties for Air Force civil engineering squadrons to ensure co-workers and base populace were informed of the status of electrical system outages
- Coordinated the construction of 30+ business facilities involving numerous departments
- Managed department personnel schedules, purchases, team assignments, and labor activities
- Developed and supervised department hazardous material and safety programs

The North Highland Company (Wells Fargo) - November 2015 to February 2016 (SharePoint Consultant)

- · Converted excel based processes over to a SharePoint business solution to reduce data validation time
- Developed user guides for administrators and users to help familiarize users with the SharePoint environment

Teksystems (T Rowe Price) - July 2015 to October 2015 (SharePoint Analyst)

- Developed online business intelligence dashboards pages for management to track project activities (live data streaming)
- Converted paper and excel based forms to web-based forms using InfoPath and Nintex to automate the job request process
- Conducted one on one training sessions for company power users to help reduce dependency on IT department for training
- Configured SharePoint search web parts to automatically filter content based on user credentials

- Collaborated with local and satellite business units to complete projects
- Produced SharePoint training videos to improve end user adoption

Serco - November 2010 to July 2015 (Corporate SharePoint Analyst)

- Managed Colorado Springs SharePoint staff, projects and trouble tickets
- SharePoint subject matter expert lead for corporate projects in North America
- Co-Authored SharePoint governance documentation for North American division
- Designed portal sites & security structure for multiple 2007, 2010, 2013, and O365 SharePoint environments
- Responsible for the maintenance, management and day-to-day operations of SharePoint for 23,000 users
- Interpreted functions and technical specifications, and systems design to recommend and implement innovative custom solutions
- · Responsible for permissions set up and audit, document libraries, and content management
- Provided UI elements customization including, out-of-the box web parts, InfoPath forms, workflows and imagery design
- Assembled dashboards using SharePoint Designer, Excel Services (Power View/Power Pivot), Visio Services and Performance Point Services
- Responsible for SharePoint collaboration project management; provided interface between the users and the developers
- Guided and trained users on platform best practices; end-user incident resolution, problem analysis and customer support

HQ Air Force Space Command - June 2008 to October 2010 (SharePoint Site Manager)

- Responsible for the governance, maintenance, and administration of SharePoint sites and portals for 1,000 users
- Designed, developed and maintained customized components; workflow, InfoPath, navigation, branding, web parts, and dashboards; OOTB SharePoint features and functionality
- Provided content management for pages, documents, enterprise lists, libraries, subsites, workflow
- Establish and maintain customized and general permissions; 500+ users
- Provided end user support and troubleshooting
- Liaison between internal / external customers and developers

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp Certificate
University College Center for Professional Development, University of Denver, CO (2019)

BS-Management/Marketing, Park University, MO (2004)

CERTIFICATIONS

Security+ (Exp. Date: Dec 2020)

CURRENT SECURITY CLEARANCE

Active Clearance (Mar 2019 - Department of Defense)